Mohiadeen Batcha

Senior systems engineer with 4.5+ year experience seeking a position to efficiently utilize my knowledge, skills and abilities for the growth of the organization and build my professional career. Quick learner and enthusiastic about venturing into new domains.

32/40N1, Ramathal layout,
Dasampalayam road,
Mettupalayam – 641305
Coimbatore
(91) 9597012726
batcha.ashik15@gmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/mohiadeen

EXPERIENCE

Infosys Ltd., Trivandrum— Technology Analyst

AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

- Certified **SAFe 5 Agile Practitioner** following strict Agile methodologies in the Development lifecycle.
- Experience in migrating on-premise data centers to Microsoft Azure for scalability & benefits along with the hands-on knowledge in the Cloud Adoption framework, a phase before the migration occurs.
- Exploring the Big data tools like Apache Kafka, Spark, Hadoop to process petabytes of real-customer data on daily basis.

Infosys Ltd., Belgium— *Technology Analyst*

NOVEMBER 2019 - AUGUST 2021

- Working closely with the clients and vendor in onsite assignment for provisioning 300+ DASH/OTT channels for Belgacom IPTV.
- Knowledge on **H.264 SD/HD compression techniques.**
- **Design, build and manage the ELK** (Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kibana) cluster for centralized logging and search functionalities for the App.
- Built a complete E2E monitoring dashboard which correlates the stats from all the Head-end components along with the real customer statistics which plays a major role in deciding the launch of the set-top box.
- Skilled in monitoring servers using Nagios and using ELK Stack Elasticsearch Kibana.

Infosys Ltd., Trivandrum— *Senior Systems Engineer*

JULY 2018 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Exploring and Developing the new uABR features to the set-top box architecture.
- Actively involved in discussions with client on requirements elicitation and estimation.
- Leading the Systems Management team in planning and **configuring the network** systems and routers.
- Mentored the peers by handling training sessions on System management & Android
 Open Source Platform (AOSP)

Infosys Ltd., Trivandrum— *Systems Engineer*

SETEMBER 2016 - JULY 2018

- Proactively taking up and executing project lifeline activities of Build manager apart from playing a pivotal role in Bug fixing.
- Played the role of Integrator of systems team by managing the client network and GIT codebase.

SKILLS

-batcha

Languages: C, C++, Python, Java

Development Tools: Atom, PyCharm,
Eclipse, Visual Code, Android Studio

Web Technology: HTML5, CSS,

Bootstrap

Database: Oracle SQL

Version Control Systems: Git
OS: Linux, Windows, MacOS
Cloud Technology: Azure

Monitoring tools: Nagios, ELK Stack.

Wireshark. Wanulator

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Insta Award for developing Audio and subtitle feature on STB (2017).

Insta Award for contributing myself in the multiple development features like Software download, Bug fix, CR and build tracks (2017).

Insta Award for taking up and executing project lifeline activities of Build manager, Systems & Networks management apart from playing a pivotal role in Bug fixing tracks (2017).

High Performer at Infosys Internship Training (2016).

Infosys Ltd., Mysore— Systems Engineer Trainee

FEBRUARY 2016 - JULY 2016

- Trained in Java, SQL, C, C++ and networking concepts.
- Completed a project on Smart Store Management system & Data Usage Billing project for cellular networks using Java Server Faces, Hibernate and Oracle SQL.
- Completed Internship training as a High Performer at Infosys Limited.

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: AZ-900 Azure

Fundamentals

Certified AGILE SAFe® 5 Practitioner

Certified by HP Software Education for undertaking "HP Software Automation Basic – ALM, UFT, VuGen & LR" course study

EDUCATION

Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College, Coimbatore *B.Tech in Information Technology*

JUNE 2012 - MAY 2016 CGPA- 7.09/10

Vijayalakshmi Matric Higher Secondary School, Sirumugai

JUNE 2010 - MAY 2012 GPA- 90.8%

Mahajana Higher Secondary School, Mettupalyam

MAY 2010 GPA- 94.8%

PROJECTS

uABR Content Delivery — Provisioning and Monitoring the DASH/OTT streams for a prominent telecom operator in Belgium

- Exploring the head-end components and optimizing the architecture to enhance the streaming on the OTT for various services like Live, Catch-up, NPVR and VOD.
- Python scripts generated to perform Automation testing on Head-end features like VHE, Origin, DRM, CDN via Nagios monitoring tool.
- Generated Key Performance Reports (KPI) on a daily/weekly/monthly basis (via ELK Stack) to the Client management for deciding the launch of the upcoming release.
- Configured Nagios to send Alerts to the Duty guards if any of the network components are running into trouble.
- Developed a statistics dashboard in Grafana to monitor all the Head-end components along with the Real customer traffic. Also generating a daily Report to the team and management.

Android Set Top Box — Developing the software for a prominent telecom operator in Belgium

- Working on uABR streaming technology to let the STB analyze the external parameter and request the manifest which is suitable.
- Developed the Audio and subtitle feature for the set-top box by building a complete end-to-end topology between middleware and UI.
- Developed Software download via unicast and multicast using C and C++.
- Developed the Backend free streaming feature (BEPless) of the STB by building a whole new architecture to stream using caches in C and Python.
- Lead the Release management process by automatically integrating the code changes from different tracks and performing a release using Git and Jenkins.
- Contributed in debugging and fixing major issues like Black screen in Live, glitches in Netflix streaming, stability issues.
- Application is built on a customized Android Open Source Project (AOSP) which uses C and C++ for middleware and Python for UI.

PES — Personal Security Application for iOS

- Used Swift and Objective-C for the application development.
- A secured iOS mobile application with various features like Requesting police, Geofence, Escort Me, Follow friend
- Worked with various gesture recognizers and frameworks.
- Experience in importing external frameworks into the iOS mobile application.

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent

Malayalam - Intermediate

Tamil - Native